[Music]
So another way of looking at learning with
learning control. Right, so I'm going to think about how I can
learn control
using a value iteration code of approach. Right, so what I want, so it's
my
target. Right, and it's my current estimate of
something. Right, so remember, I'm learning
the cue function. So, what the cue function
tells
me to
take an action is what is the action given in
the cue argument.
Right, and then behave optimally. Then, after it,
the first action is what I take. Right, there's no
question of optimality. Or anything about it, it can be the thing.
Right, I'm looking at it. Right, I should move away very quickly. After
writing something on the board, I'll wave me away.
Right, I mean, peel it off. Right, so what
I'm really looking for is what I want to say. The
expected value of that is what I get
for performing
a plus or minus times.  v star of what ever comes
after
words correct
but we know about star and can rate star in
terms of k function how to
star
max best rate no working time function
ra so this not equal to now can do our
sto caustic updating rule this is
my
target this is my current estimate
so putting this together can just right rule like this rate will be rule so
target
minus current estimate right people get ra tr
to yer we're just
trying to take the definition of k function
expected value of return now looking
definition of q function expected
optimal q function expected value
of this
expression now im converting this into
update
role now i can put in the rest of it around this so what is a nice thing ya just like
in the expected sum i don't have to
pick the action before hand i can pick the
action after words also bz am l ly doing
The max so I don't have to do the pick an
action first and then apply it rat I can move this with in
the
loop to remove this rat I can flip this
around
basically why is it important
why am I so concerned that is because
or so there are a couple of things or so one
thing the most straight forward answer is it could come back
to as in which case I'd change
the value function right I'd use one a for
updating this or using the a I'm
going to take rat but then I would actually
perform a different a in each case my return c what I was
trying to do here was
substitute my return right so I am
going to use π p gamma this because that is a
sample of the return rat so a sample
of the return that means I should actually be
sampling an angle to whatever updating I'm
making but  What I'll be doing is I'll be
sampling a different
action if I pick another action after I do the
update. Okay, so I'll be breaking the
equation so this is an approximation for the
return. So that's the reason we need to pick the
action before hand and then stick with it
right and left on when we see how we'll be
using an approximation. We talk about
contextual bandits right and
talked about policy parameterization. Like that,
you can use a value function
parameterization. One you use is that you don't have to come back
to the same state because of the
functional form. If you change the value in one
state, it may change it in some other state as well. So,
the whole policy would get messed up.
So it becomes a little tricky. So,
essentially, the trick that I'm doing the
update will be something called a messed up version of
the trick that I'm
taking. So, it might lead to some trouble.  In
convergence of one action, one might be performing a
ratio of it to perform an action performing it
okay or why you keep changing the policy anyway do your
extension of the policy anyway so it okay don't
know what the policy is as an
exponential function of just 1 if 1
and 2 go to zero it converge to something
and as long as 3 returns it if I'm using 1 then I'm
exactly rolling it out rate I can roll it out or
rolling it out return what ever I'm using if I'm using 1
the action I took then I'm
fine
or 1 value of this policy if you start off with 1 you could actually make it
a valid policy and you could
start off with 1 zero in this case it's a
uniform random
policy i.e. just 1 action with equal
probability to begin with so you can do the same thing in 1
space
okay or I don't have to accurately pick 1 or 2 just
pick 1 action after 1  8 I also put the thing in
brackets, I'll come to that, that's why I put that
pick action according to the kst output, but you can see the difference between this
algorithm and that algorithm, right nothing much except for that
simple change in the update
rule, if you add alpha and asn properly, it actually is the optimal policy, the second
k terminal
policy
provided, provided alpha properly decays alpha properly decays the k terminal policy,
and this one I either decreases both alpha and asn properly decays the k
terminal policy  For example, if
for alpha, you have the last
averaging formula, then so or tell
me one thing that will fit the condition, then so summation
alpha should be infinity, summation alpha should be bounded by less than
infinity, then so basically the condition for
alpha so sum all alphas, so as to put an
alpha t there and sum over all alpha t, so
just summing o alpha t should be infinity, summing o
alpha t should be bounded by less than
infinity, so as the condition alpha t = infinity tells you that you are
making enough
updates, alpha t = squared, go converge to a
point, less than infinity, means that you already
stop making
updates,
you are doing well, but the rest
of the class is about, but so this am
not right, it is probably the most popular
sum,
you said, not rows, second most popular, to
first most popular, called
why
Learning
so logically came
first the proposal in like
84 the proposal 84 as convergence 88 and
some and learning was proposed by Chris
Takin in
89 as regeneration
91 92 again date sometimes are so surprisingly
both Takin and Raman from
England only are for real chem from England it's
amazing to see more amazing about why learning so I don't care what is the
sequence of taking
action using approximate time I don't care about action in why learning I do have to supply according
to any
action in fact next action acute need not come from at pv in arbitrarily reset it is a
simulation model can arbitrary reset to
some other state rate and then supply one action
from there update cue learning and then go and
take action  From some else some other
state update using queue learning can just do
a proper
asynchronous generalized policy iteration kind of
an approach just sample from all over the
place just take one step each and keep
updating it but still it is better to update it
along path like we saw in the
argument for RDP right if you update it
along path it is more meaningful because
value should have more like path along which path it is more meaningful because value should have more like path so this thing need not be added
to the path so I can just take one action as soon as I can
follow any rule so I can
update
next if I am not sampling according to the
path it only tells me which action I am going to
update next so why do you want to pick
according to this so
that you can just do like in RDP so
you can focus the updates along the most
like path so  The reason you do it in a
good fashion is you quickly want to converge to
the most likely path. You're going to take an
optimal policy, and you want to do the
updates along that most likely path.
You use this for a
learning advantage. You can continue to
explore and while exploring, you learn something by
taking into account
exploration. So, learning is by learning. But if you choose to be interested in what
you're learning or not, you can take into
account the fact
that you're doing
exploration. So, we'll
talk about a
simple grid world problem called the
cliff
world. So, two square marks in a red
cliff. So, agent wander over the cliff and get off
of mine
100 and then top it off. Agent also does just that.
Get off of mine 100 and it goes back
to the beginning. So, start
going over again.  Now you get a
reward of minus 0 for every time step
that you
move okay so everything is deterministic so
for every time step that you move you will
get a reward of minus 0
okay and you have to try to get from the
start to the goal as quickly as possible no
gamma here gamma is one to never say no gamma do mean gamma
zero it means gamma is one okay
and so what you think will happen and while
learning I use
a asan greedy accent selection asan let's say I
fix it at
0.1 I'm not going to reduce asan I will
fix asan at punt w
okay so what you think is the policy what do you think q
learning will do what y think sirs will do well we said both will
learn optimal
policies what is
optimal policy here ra so if
you go up or you go left right right right right so this is
optimal policy os i want to write
down  Optimal Policy Also
can just right down arrow everyone
can right down arrow everyone and right every
accept last column
down terminal
policy
x Optimal Policy
Least Far
State Far State Your Choice Cannot Go Right and
Down Far State Terminal Policy Rat Luck
Learning Fast Terminal
Policy
Yes Some P In this
case it's because I'm fixing a point
right so what happens next will show up
a point later so it takes a
safer and safer row if I give you more rows right it will probably go but then this is too small
it basically needs two extra
moves to fall off the cliff and I've given it like
10 moves in between to take this
to
explore it will take two to explore
moves right so it will try to stay as far away if it just goes away right it will be just two
moves right now this is three moves so that's why it will try to go as
far  Away is possible
because the reward is sufficiently negative and
said mine 100 rat so it's really really bad
negative reward so it's trying to go father and
father away so this is the difference between sasa
and ky learning right so it takes into account
the fact that you are doing
exploration right while ky learning might
learn the optimal
policy right it also ends up killing you more on while learning
the optimal
policy right there are also
more naive answers for this because if you continue
to explore right not at all but slightly less
comparing reasons if you are going to continue to
explore after you finish learning right it's better to
learn
a policy through sas than through ky learning
because ky learning assumes that event is
going to be
executed policy right but that is a reason
for us not to execute optimal policy really  There's a
reason why we shouldn't use optimal policy well even after successive
learning is non-stationary and now non-stationary. So if your
world isn't changing then
you can just be behaving well after some
time but some things might happen.
Right, and suppose you're robotically learning in
a world. Right, so it's possible that
obstacles can be moved around. Right, so
you don't want to become so resentful that you're
completely unaware of
the option to keep being able to
explore and discover new things. So you don't want to
turn off your assignment. Right,
in such cases, it's better to use sequences than queue learning because queue learning is kind of ignorant
of
exploration at all. Right, and it
converges to optimal policy and then
sticks there.
Right, so right,
and so the problem with converging
to optimal policy and sticking  Then this
rat, if I want to keep my attention on or I keep falling
off the
cliff, every single move I make, every single
exploration move I make, and I keep falling off the
cliff, so the expected reward I get for
executing this optimal policy will be far less than what
my agent believes it should be getting because the
agent is ignoring the
exploration. Okay, so that is the crucial
difference between Q-learning and
SARSA. You would like to use
SARSA in many
cases. If Q-learning is large, then Q-learning is good, then it is
no danger in that Q-learning is
actually good in some aspects.
[Music]
Then there is no danger in that the state space is very
large, so should the size of the state space matter?
X-
plore
exploring can explore much more than
SARSA. But an exploration policy can
completely behave.  Completely random
and still terminal policy in some cases is a form of
learning by
policy
method or arbitrary action or a terminal
policy estimation policy for me is an
optimal policy because the policy is completely random so that is one reason you would want to use
learning in a large state space because I can
behave arbitrarily so I get to
explore larger functions of the state
space
slow everything will be slow everything will be slow everything will be slow because it will be slower because it is a slower process
[music] I'm
not 100% sure about the convergence rate
between linear learning and sequential learning I'm not sure I'm not sure
about the
convergence rates I do believe that random learning
converges faster than random learning
in general and I'm not sure about the large state
space issue but I have to look it up
but you should note these are the basic
algorithms that I use  Operate in large state
spaces or be using something else on top
of this should be using plain learning
and large state spaces so there are other
issues that will come into play but I'm not
100% sure about comparing rates of
convergence between learning and large state spaces
so any other question on this to so I have
these three actually we talk about
expected states as well rate
and in that fat you can think of all kinds of
hybrid algorithms rate so for example you can think of all kinds
of algorithms rate will
take one step to steps according to the
current policy and then you make some mean but something like this so this is this
part on
policy so part of policy rate so
hybrid kind of thing so you can do all kinds of
different kinds of sampler for
your value
function so in fact it's more common to use
The Q function
there so still applies to policy everything is on
policy but I'm using more of the actual
samples and
less of the boot strapping because I'm
discounted by a larger power of gamma so the
total contribution of the boot strapping will be coming
down so I can do lots of
modification to the return so in fact there was a
time when we were trying to get a
reinforcement learning agent to
play what is the thing called
hockey right so
someone wanted to get a real agent to play
hockey in fact he was building a physical
system that was going to move the slider
around and he wanted to use real to control
it and then it turned out in the simulator at least that he had built
using a three
step return like rt+1 rt+2 rt+3 then then
the Q function of the rest turned
out to  gave a better performance for what ever reason
right so it's it's kind of tied
to the stoic city in the system and how far
ahead is the system predictable and so
on so forth so I think it turns out the at
least far at least three steps into the
future the system was more or less
predictable of it so very complicated
thing easy to figure out what is right look ahead to you should be
using for the returns okay so they
more or less done with chapter
[music]
[applause] six